Juan Casse Los Angeles, CA (310) 913-7306 jcasse@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/juan-casse gitlab.com/jcasse

## Software Engineer

Trained in machine learning, my passion lies in software engineering. My ideal job combines software development with implementing of machine learning algorithms and Al. Years as a graduate student researcher gave me the tools to work independently while a previous engineering career in the field of medical device manufacturing gave me the experience of working on large-scale projects with cross-fucntional teams.

#### **Technical Tools**

**Languages:** C · C++ · Python · Java · Objective-C · Bash · R · Matlab · SQL · Lisp · £TEX · XML · JSON · YAML **Productivity:** Emacs · Vim · R Studio · Android Studio · Xcode · Eclipse · Git · Gerrit · Jira · Confluence · Slack

**Platforms:** Linux · Docker · Tomcat · SQL Server · Oracle · JDBC · OpenGL **Graphing:** Gnuplot · Graphviz · Xfig · AutoCAD · Bokeh · ggplot2 · wxWidgets

## Experience in Industry

### Trusted Autonomy, a Beyond Limits company

Leader in industrial-grade Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) software

## **AI Software Engineer**

- Develop artificial intelligence software
- · Implement machine learning algorithms

### InAuth, Inc., an American Express company

Leader in mobile-first authentication and fraud prevention for mobile applications and browsers

### SDET

July 2016 - October 2017

October 2017 - present

• Developed cross-platform, test automation framework for the company's mobile SDK products. It runs on Linux and OS X, operates on Android and iOS devices, is extensible and provides end-to-end automation, writing results to an MS Excel spreadsheet in the cloud. It reduces a month of work of three QA testers to two hours.

### Children's Hospital Los Angeles

Award-winning, non-profit, research hospital providing life-saving care to children

#### **Data Scientist**

December 2014 - July 2016

- Developed algorithm to diagnose patients. It transformed each patient's heterogeneous, messy and irregularly sampled longitudinal data from electronic health records into a fixed-length feature vector, relative to every other patient in the ICU. The interrelation between variables and their timing information was modeled in a principled way as a marked point process. The number of clusters was automatically selected by the algorithm.
- Implemented packages in R and Python for data cleaning and analysis

### Google, Inc.

Multinational, technology company specializing in Internet-related services and products

### **Software Engineering Intern**

**June 2013 - September 2013** 

- Contributed to open source software, Flexible I/O Tester (fio)
- Developed Linux utility in C to test data integrity and retention of storage devices

### Experience in Academia

## **University of California Riverside**

Public research university part of the University of California system

### **Graduate Student Researcher**

**June 2012 - September 2014** 

• Implemented clustering algorithms (20K lines of C++ code) in support of my research

# Associate Instructor

April 2012 - June 2012

• Taught CS 14 Introduction to Data Structures and Algorithms

# **Teaching Assistant**

**September 2009 - June 2013** 

• Held laboratory sessions, graded assignments, and held office hours for various CS courses

# Harvey Mudd College

Top-ranked college of science, engineering and mathematics

## Instructor

January 2011 - May 2011

Taught CS 151 Artificial Intelligence

Juan Casse page 2 of 2

## **Previous Professional Experience**

### Lifescan, a Johnson & Johnson company

Manufacturer of blood glucose monitoring systems for home and hospital use

### **Staff Engineer**

January 2002 - December 2004

- Introduced new technology automation to our manufacturing process
- Worked closely with machine builders through conceptual design, reviews and validation

## **Senior Manufacturing Engineer**

August 1997 - January 2002

- Improved process yield from 75% to 85% through 6-sigma projects
- Integrated vision inspection systems on all manufacturing lines to ensure correct labeling

## **Baxter Biotech Group Fenwal Division**

Medical device manufacturer of products used in the delivery of fluids/drugs and hemodialysis

## **Project Engineer - Factory Automation**

September 1993 - September 1997

- · Designed and built automated manufacturing equipment for the company's facilities worldwide
- Supervised personnel and coordinated work in automation group's machine shop
- Integrated radiation-based sterilization process

# Other Technical Experience

Web IDE (2018) Web-based IDE, deployed in Docker. Python, Flask, Apache Http Server, Ace, GoldenLayout

Experimenter (2015) Multi-threaded, GUI-based workflow tool. C++, wxWidgets

Automatic Grader (2012) Coding assignment grading and reporting system. Bash, C++

Interactive 3D Visualization (2011) GUI for viewing a clustering of cubed data. C++, OpenGL

Convoy Routing (2007) Genetic algorithm for optimal scheduling of convoys on shared roads. C++, Java

## Education

### Ph.D. in Computer Science (GPA 3.9) University of California, Riverside

December 2014

• Dissertation: Automatic Co-clustering for Social Network and Medical Data

# M.S. in Computer Science (GPA 3.9) California State University, Long Beach

May 2008

Thesis: Convoy Routing and scheduling using Augmented Beam Search, RSBS

### B.S. in Electrical Engineering (GPA 2.5) Marquette University, Milwaukee

August 1992

• Senior Project: Robotic arm to demonstrate cell manufacturing to future classes

### **Publications**

Islam, Kazi T., Shelton, Christian R., Casse, Juan I. and Wetzel, Randall (2017). Marked Point Process for Severity of Illness Assessment. Proceedings of Machine Learning for Healthcare 2017. JMLR W&C Track Volume 68.

Casse, Juan Ignacio (2014). **Automatic Co-clustering for Social Network and Medical Data**. Ph.D. Dissertation, University of California Riverside, Riverside, CA.

Casse, J., Shelton, C., Hanneman, R. (2013). A new criterion function for exploratory blockmodeling for structural and regular equivalence. Social Networks, 35(1), 32–50.

Casse, J.I., Shelton, C.R., and Hanneman R.A. (2011). **Alternating Optimization Algorithm for Block-modeling Two-way Two-mode Data with Unknown Number of Clusters**. Regular Session on Social Networks for the 2011 ASA.

Goldstein, D., Shehab, T., Casse, J., and Lin, H. (2010). **On the formulation and solution of the convoy routing problem**. Transportation Research Part E: Logistics and Transportation Review, 46(4), 520.

Casse, J.I. (2008). Convoy Routing and Scheduling using Augmented Beam Search RSBS. Master's thesis, California State University, Long Beach, CA.